César Garro-Marín

Ph.D Candidate • Economics • Boston University

⑤ (857) 425-9404 • ☑ cesarlgm@bu.edu • ☐ cesargarromarin.com • cesarlgm

About me

Ph.D candidate in Economics with a strong background in data analysis and causal inference. Interested in economist and data scientist positions. Over 8 years of experience in Stata and R. A team player and a manager, having worked on multiple cross-functional projects. Lead project development & management, as well as data collection, coding, statistical & econometric analysis.

Work Experience Boston University

2019 - Graduate Student Researcher — Research Assistant

Researched the role of local labor markets in explaining gender inequality, the role of firms in explaining labor market outcomes, & how people invest in skills. Used rich micro data to test hypotheses, infer causal mechanisms, & provide valuable insights on how the local environment & individual decisions affect labor market outcomes.

- Analyzed large & intricate datasets to extract valuable insights on gender inequality, local labor markets, earnings disparities within the US academic sector, & people's skill investment. Worked with large census & survey data from multiple countries and created compelling data visualizations.
- Created & oversaw multiple research projects on labor & development economics using reduced-form & structural research designs
- Responsible for presenting findings in internal departmental seminars as well as international conferences

2020 - Lead Researcher

Partnered with Indonesian policymakers & a fellow BU student to assess the impact of vocational school training programs, identified effectiveness challenges, & delivered practical recommendations to policymakers for program improvement. Successfully secured \$75,000 from external grants.

- Defined effectiveness metrics & designed an experimental evaluation for the program, which was then deployed in coordination with the Indonesian Ministry of Education
- Designed & deployed an original survey to collect data from 2,000 teachers & managed a team of research assistants & surveyors
- Responsible for presenting findings & policy recommendations to senior policymakers.

Bac-Credomatic Bank

2013 – 2014 Data Analyst

Provided critical product insights to senior bank executives by analyzing credit card portfolio data.

- Designed & executed data analysis for the bank's senior management & other internal clients, informing decisions about credit policy, credit offering targeting, & debt collection targeting
- Monitored industry trends & measured product performance to proactively identify opportunities for improvement & growth
- Lead automation of regular reports, & maintained robust documentation of procedures & software

Teaching Experience

Teaching Fellow @ Boston University

2020 Economics of Labor Markets

Fall 2019 Poverty and Discrimination

2018 – 2019 Principles of Microeconomics

Instructor @ Universidad de Costa Rica

2014 – 2015 Principles of Economics

- Developed lesson plans, homework, and grading schema, and wrote detailed feedback on homework and exams
- Held weekly office hours for individualized tutoring

Skills

Project

Experimental design Long-term project management Team management Data visualization

Data

Use of large data Statistical analysis & testing Causal inference

Communication

Science writing Annotation guidelines Public speaking

Technologies

R
MATLAB
Stata
Git
SQL

•••

Languages

English Spanish French

••••

Education

expected Aug-2023

d **Ph.D. Economics**Boston University,
Boston, MA

2017 M.A. Economics & Finance CEMFI, Madrid, Spain

2013 **B.A. Economics** Universidad de Costa Rica, San José, Costa Rica

References

References available upon request